Guide to the Jack and Rebecca Matlock Papers, 1930s-2017 RL.11082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Foreign Service, 1950-1991
  - National Security Council / Special Assistant to President Reagan, 1983-1986
    - Notes by JM: US-Soviet strategies, relationships, summit ideas, negotiations, 1985 (Box 50)
      Assorted pages and notes; additional notes located in the chronological notes files from 1985
    - Notes by JM: Shultz-Shevardnadze meetings, 1985 (Box 50)
      Multiple meetings represented, including July, Oct., Nov.
    - Notes by JM, 1985 (Box 50)
      General notes, messages
    - Notes/Schedules for JM, 1985 Jan.-Dec.; 12 folders (Box 50)
      Chronological files kept by JM with notes, schedules, and accompanying documentation for his activities in 1985. Includes major meetings as well as routine to-do lists.
    - Guests lists and schedules, 1985 (Box 50)
    - Invitations, programs, and tickets, 1985 (Box 50)
    - Telephone numbers and messages for JM, 1985 (Box 50)
    - Official travel records, reimbursements, 1985; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - US-USSR arms negotiations with Shultz and Gromyko, 1985 Jan. (Box 51)
    - Reagan inauguration and related events, 1985 Jan. 18-21 (Box 51)
    - Aspen Institute conferences at Wye Plantation on US-Soviet Relations: Planning for the Future, 1985 Feb. 7-10, Mar. 7-9 (Box 51)
    - Thatcher working visit to Washington, 1985 Feb. 19-21 (Box 51)
    - Bush's trip to Moscow for Konstantin Chernenko's funeral, 1985 Mar. 13 (Box 51)
    - Eighth Biennial American-German Conference, 1985 Mar. 28-31 (Box 51)
    - Strategic Defense, Strategic Modernization, and Arms Control panel at Naval War College, 1985 Apr. 11-13 (Box 51)
    - Letter from Reagan to Austrian President Kirchschlaeger, Vienna (photocopy), 1985 May 9 (Box 51)
    - Letter from Reagan to Gorbachev (photocopy), 1985 May 11 (Box 51)
      Re: Baldrige's visit to Moscow and future negotiations
    - Shultz visit to Vienna, 1985 May 13-15 (Box 51)
    - US-USSR joint trade talks, Moscow, 1985 May 20-22 (Box 51)
    - Chiefs of Mission conference at American embassy, London, 1985 Jun. 7-8 (Box 51)
    - Shultz's visit to Helsinki for 10th anniversary of CSCE, 1985 Jul. 29-Aug. 1 (Box 51)
    - Reagan-Shevardnadze meeting: advanced talking points, notes, 1985 Sept. 27 (Box 51)
    - Shultz visit to Brussels for NATO consultations, 1985 Oct. 15 (Box 51)
    - Reagan to New York for UN address, 1985 Oct. 23-25 (Box 51)
    - Shultz to Europe (Helsinki, Moscow, Reykjavik) pre-summit, 1985 Oct. 31-Nov. 6 (Box 51)
    - Reagan Voice of America address, 1985 Nov. 9 (Box 51)
    - Reagan-Gorbachev summit, Geneva, 1985 Nov. 16-21; 6 folders (Box 51)
      Includes summit schedules, briefing books, notes by JM, planning and talking points, memoranda, logistical and transit information, press accounts and public perceptions, and 2 letters intended for Raisa Gorbachev
    - Reagan address to Joint Session of Congress, reporting on Geneva, 1985 Nov. 21 (Box 51)
    - Trip to Bonn and Berlin for Aspen Institute Berlin and NATO Roundtable, 1985 Dec. 1-6 (Box 51)
    - Kennan Institute meeting report, including JM on US-Soviet Relations, 1985 Dec. 18 (Box 51)
    - Incoming clippings, reports, publications, 1986; 6 folders (Box 52)
    - Incoming unclassified cables, 1986 (Box 52)
    - Correspondence, 1986; 7 folders (Box 52)
      Includes 3 folders of Christmas cards and other personal greetings.
    - White House press releases, briefings, and transcripts, 1986 (Box 52)
    - Memoranda, 1986; 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Free Afghanistan Alliance letter to Reagan, with photographs, 1986 Jan. 24, Apr. 28 (Box 53)
      Includes photographs of Afghan War victims, refugees in Oval Office, as well as JM response opting to not share with Gorbachev
    - JM draft demarche to Soviet Embassy re: Daniloff detainment, 1986 (Box 53)
    - Reagan letters to Gorbachev, drafts, 1986 (Box 53)
      Various versions of JM drafts and notes re: Reagan's communications with Gorbachev throughout 1986, including February, July, and other points.
    - Chernyayev to Gorbachev 1986 June 9 memo by JM, 1986 June 16 (Box 53)
      Fictional memo exploring Kremlin's administration/viewpoint, shared with Reagan (who kept a copy). Photocopy.
    - Speech notes, general, 1986 (Box 53)
    - Official travel records, reimbursements, 1986 (Box 53)
    - Geneva Exchanges Initiative memoranda, 1986 (Box 53)
    - German and American Perspectives on East-West Relations after the Geneva Summit: conference at Wilson Center, 1986 Feb. 9-11 (Box 53)
    - Impact symposium, Vanderbilt, Nashville, 1986 Feb. 21 (Box 53)
    - US public diplomacy in Europe conference at the American Embassy, London, 1986 Mar. 3-4 (Box 53)
    - Washington seminar for the William Benton Fellows, Chicago, 1986 Mar. 6-8 (Box 53)
    - University of Michigan briefing on Soviet affairs, 1986 Mar. 9 (Box 53)
    - Arden House Conference: Mikhail Gorbachev, One Year Later, 1986 Mar. 21-23 (Box 53)
    - The Future of US-USSR Relations: lessons from forty years without world war, University of Texas symposium, 1986 Apr. 2-4 (Box 53)
    - Reagan-Dobrynin meeting, 1986 Apr. 8 (Box 53)
    - Institute for East-West Relations conference: Improving East-West Relations, 1986 Apr. 18-20 (Box 53)
    - Ditchley conference: Divided Germany and the Future of Europe; JM trip to London, 1986 May 9-12 (Box 53)
    - American Committee on East-West Accord annual meeting, 1986 May 23 (Box 53)
    - University of Washington speech by JM: The US-Soviet Relationship: What are the Prospects?, 1986 May 30 (Box 53)
      Includes drafts and edits
    - American Women for International Understanding luncheon, 1986 Jun. 6 (Box 53)
    - Common Security Programme consultancy papers, 1986 June (Box 53)
      Re: nuclear weapons
    - Foreign Service Institute: Senior Seminar, 1985-1986 (Box 53)
      Materials for 28th session
    - US-Soviet Relations symposium, Brussels, 1986 Jun. 30-Jul. 2 (Box 53)
    - Public Choices on Nuclear Arms Control and US-Soviet Relations, American Enterprise Institute, 1986 Jul. 18 (Box 53)
    - Aspen Institute Executive Seminar, 1986 Aug. 3-16 (Box 53)
    - Naval War College address by JM, Newport, RI, 1986 Sept. 2 (Box 53)
    - Chautauqua-style conference in Latvia, including address by JM in Jurmala, 1986 Sept. 15-19; 5 folders (Box 53)
      Includes drafts of JM's speech in multiple languages; press coverage and reactions, including correspondence from listeners; administration's internal discussions for participation in conference without recognizing Baltic States.
    - Reagan-Gorbachev summit, Reykjavik, 1986 Oct. 9-12; 2 folders (Box 54)
      Planning materials, briefing books, JM notes from different meetings; notes from unidentified participants; press coverage and collected reactions
    - Institute for East-West Security Studies anniversary dinner, 1986 Oct. 17 (Box 54)
    - Trip to Copenhagen, Oslo, Netherlands, 1986 Oct. 19-23 (Box 54)
    - Trip to Vienna, Paris, 1986 Nov. 4-7 (Box 54)
    - Congressional Young Leaders Conference, Washington, 1986 Dec. 9 (Box 54)
    - Reagan's New Year's message to the Soviet people, 1986 Dec. 24 (Box 54)
      Speech drafts for taping of message. Als includes internal memos re: rejection of Soviets to participation in mutual greetings for New Year's 1987.
    - Invitations, programs, 1986; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Conferences and lecture schedules, 1986 (Box 54)
      Drafts of JM's schedule for 1986
    - Notes/Schedules for JM, 1986 Jan.-Dec.; 11 folders (Box 54)
      Chronological files kept by JM with notes, schedules, and accompanying documentation for his activities in 1986. Includes major meetings as well as routine to-do lists. Missing Nov. 1986.
  - USSR ambassadorship, 1987-1991
    Jack Matlock was appointed to be the US Ambassador to the Soviet Union in January 1987, and served from April 1987 until August 1991. This subseries contains materials documenting his work, and Rebecca's service as ambassador's wife, including their formal appearances at various events in Moscow; hosting US officials and other guests at the embassy and at Spaso House, the ambassador's residence; and their frequent travels to various places within the Soviet Union territory to visit and represent the United States. Materials are grouped chronologically by year, and then subsequently arranged by format: Reports/Clippings, Cables, Memoranda, Correspondence, Topics, and Events.
    The subseries contains correspondence, memoranda, incoming cables and reports, and other government documents and administrative items relating to specific issues and events. Of note are the visit by the Gorbachevs to the United States in 1987; the Reagan-Gorbachev summit in Moscow in 1988; and the Bush-Gorbachev summits in Malta (1989) and Moscow (1991). There are a couple of thank-you letters included following these major events from Presidents Reagan and Bush. Recurring themes include security at the Moscow embassy; exit visas for Soviet dissidents; coverage of US activities and attitudes toward the US in the Soviet press; and interpretations of Soviet activities/attitudes by US officials. The Matlocks actively participated in various US cultural expositions throughout the Soviet Union, including attending opening exhibits for Information USA during 1987 and 1988, which toured several Soviet states. They also frequently hosted Soviet and American guests at Spaso House, including poets, musicians, and performers, and the subseries includes official guest lists and planning materials discussing the intended messaging and tone for these cultural exchanges. This subseries includes drafts of different speeches delivered by Matlock, typically in Russian, when he was the invited guest at different Soviet academies or organizations. There is a significant amount of material relating to Matlock's speech in Latvian at the Riga Chautauqua conference, which the US participated in despite not recognizing the Soviets' occupation of Latvia.
    There is much accompanying information for the events in this subseries held in the Diaries Series and in the Writings Series -- Rebecca's accounts and perspectives are included in several essays as well as in the Dear Everybody Letters, held in the Writings Series.
    - Appointment of JM as ambassador to USSR, 1987 Jan.-April (Box 70)
    - Letters of congratulations on appointment to USSR ambassadorship, 1987 (Box 70)
    - Transfer and shipment of effects from Washington to Moscow, 1987 (Box 70)
    - Talking points, preparations for JM's Senate confirmation, 1987 Feb.-Mar. (Box 70)
    - JM swearing-in as ambassador, 1987 Mar.; 2 folders (Box 70)
      Includes photographs from ceremony
    - Press coverage and clippings, 1987 (Box 70)
      Collected by embassy, some re: JM and some re: other general Moscow embassy activities
    - Incoming reports, 1987; 3 folders (Box 70)
      Includes incoming cables, reference sources, published reports, and internal reports from colleagues.
    - Correspondence, 1987; 3 folders (Box 56)
      Includes professional and personal correspondence, as well as some copies of JM's outgoing letters.
    - Memoranda, 1987 (Box 56)
      Official exchanges between JM and embassy or State Dept. staff
    - American embassy Moscow facility reports, 1987 (Box 56)
      Moscow and ambassador dacha condition reports, security and surveillance materials
    - Moscow embassy personnel, other contacts, 1987 (Box 56)
      Staff and contact lists for Moscow
    - Correspondence between RM and JM while apart, 1987 (Box 56)
    - Speeches and articles by JM, 1987 (Box 56)
      Includes drafts and preparatory work
    - JM/RM invitations, programs, tickets, 1987 (Box 56)
    - JM/RM schedules, guest lists, 1987 (Box 56)
      Drafts and official schedules and guest lists for programs hosted by the Matlocks
    - Frunze Military Academy speech, 1987 May 14 (Box 56)
      Drafts and program materials, some in Russian
    - JM Speech to the International Physicians for the Prevention of Nuclear War, 1987 May 30 (Box 56)
      Drafts, notes in Russian and English re: Strategic Defense Initiative
    - "Information USA" exhibit opening, Kiev, 1987 Aug. 11-13 (Box 56)
    - Chatauqua Conference, New York, 1987 Aug. 23-28 (Box 56)
      Clippings and press coverage of conference
    - Ogonyok interview with JM, 1987 Sept. (Box 56)
    - "Information USA" exhibit, Rostov-on-Don, 1987 Oct. 13-14 (Box 56)
    - Gorbachev's visit to the U.S., 1987 Dec. 7-10 (Box 56)
      Schedules, press, and memoranda
    - EUR Chiefs of Mission Conference, Oslo, 1987 Dec. 13-14 (Box 56)
    - "Information USA" trip to Tbilisi, Georgia, 1987 Dec. 16 (Box 56)
      Includes speech drafts, gift lists, photographs of JM at exhibit opening
    - American Art of the 20th Century exhibition catalog, 1987 (Box 56)
    - Reports, clippings, and reference materials, 1988; 5 folders (Box 57)
    - Novosti Press Agency guides, 1988 (Box 57)
      Printed guides to Komsomol Democracy, Razumnovky, Lenin's works, etc. Printed in English in Moscow.
    - Incoming unclassified cables, 1988; 6 folders (Box 57)
    - Correspondence, 1988; 5 folders (Box 58)
    - JM notes, 1988 (Box 58)
    - Speeches and messages, 1988 (Box 58)
      Assorted notes and drafts of texts by JM and Reagan
    - Book orders, 1988 (Box 58)
      For JM or embassy library
    - Memoranda, 1988; 2 folders (Box 58)
      Official exchanges between embassy and State Dept. staff. Many overlaps with other correspondence files and Consecutive Files series.
    - Embassy Moscow Town Meetings, 1988 (Box 58)
      Includes newsletters, notes by JM re: meetings, phone lists, and Chiefs of Mission listings
    - Coverage and clippings of JM, 1988 (Box 58)
      Variety of press sources including interviews, coverage of JM and RM activities, etc.
    - Invitations, tickets, and programs from events, 1988 (Box 58)
      Largely collected by JM and RM's attendance at these events as ambassadors
    - Guest lists and schedules, 1988; 3 folders (Box 58)
      Drafts and proposed guest lists and schedules for both JM and RM's official and unofficial duties, including meetings and travel
    - Visit to "Moscow" Kombinat, 1988 (Box 58)
      Postcards and notes from an undated (circa 1988) visit to this communal farm
    - Remarks by JM on Martin Luther King Jr. Day, 1988 Jan. 18 (Box 58)
      Drafts, including Russian
    - "American Paintings" exhibit opening at Russian Museum, Leningrad, 1988 Jan. 21 (Box 58)
    - Evening of Poetry with Andrei Voznesensky, Vitaly Korotich, Boris Zakhoder, and William Jay Smith, Spaso House, 1988 Jan. 26 (Box 58)
      Includes poetry and translations, as well as programming, guest lists, logistics.
    - 30th Anniversary of Exchanges Agreement program, Hall of Columns, Moscow, 1988 Jan. 27 (Box 58)
      Includes JM speech text
    - Interview with Sovietskaya Rossiya, 1988 Feb 18 (Box 58)
    - Visit of Sec. of State Schultz to Helsinki, 1988 Feb. 20-21 (Box 59)
    - "Information USA" exhibit in Tashkent, 1988 Feb. 25 (Box 59)
      Includes speech text in Russian, Uzbek
    - E. Shevardnadze visit to Washington DC, 1988 Mar. 25 (Box 59)
      Memoranda and protocol lists
    - Arden House Conference: Detente Revisited?, New York, 1988 Mar. 25-27 (Box 59)
    - Lecture and visit to University of Miami, 1988 Mar. 29 (Box 59)
    - Yo-Yo Ma performance, Spaso House, 1988 Apr. 7 (Box 59)
    - Visit of Sec. of State Shultz to Geneva, Moscow, 1988 Apr. (Box 59)
      Includes press coverage, preparatory materials, schedules
    - Remarks by JM at Malinovsky Tank Academy, 1988 Apr. 29 (Box 59)
      "Glasnost and openness in U.S.-Soviet Relations," with notes/drafts in Russian
    - "Information USA" exhibit, Irkutsk, 1988 May 4-7 (Box 59)
      Schedule, information, etc.
    - Showing of "Rain Man" film, Spaso House, 1988 May 17 (Box 59)
    - Dance Theatre of Harlem reception, Spaso House, 1988 May 19 (Box 59)
      Copy of JM remarks
    - Armand Hammer 90th birthday celebration, Spaso House, 1988 May 20 (Box 59)
    - Interview with Radio Moscow, 1988 May 22-23 (Box 59)
      JM correspondence, copy of interview questions (including Russian)
    - Reagan-Gorbachev summit, Moscow, 1988 May 29-June 1; 6 folders (Box 59)
      Planning materials, memoranda, talking points, schedules and logistics, memorabilia, correspondence, and other printed materials from the planning and execution of the summit and accompanying events and excursions, as well as cables and press coverage documenting its reception and perceptions of U.S. activities around the world. Includes a letter dated June 17 from Reagan to Matlock thanking him and Rebecca for their work.
    - Reagan-Gorbachev summit, Moscow souvenir album, 1988 (Box 80)
      Created by official photographers from the Soviet Tass Agency, this bound color photobook commemorates the U.S./Soviet summit held in Moscow, May 29-June 2, 1988, presided over by President Reagan and Soviet General Secretary Gorbachev. The cloth-bound volume measures 11x17 inches, with the pages sized slightly smaller; the richly toned color images are often full-page, no borders, or smaller, with white borders. Some captions added by archivists, in consultation with RM.
    - Institute for East-West Security conference, Potsdam, 1988 June 8-9; 2 folders (Box 60)
      "New Approaches to East-West Security" conference materials, travel guides, logistics and notes
    - Vernissage of Spaso House Art collection, 1988 July 1 (Box 60)
    - July 4th television address by JM, 1988 (Box 60)
      Includes Russian text, drafts
    - "Information USA" exhibit, Magnitogorsk, 1988 July 13-14; 2 folders (Box 60)
      Includes photographs from RM and JM visit to Magnitogorsk (believed to be from this visit)
    - 19th All-Union CSPU Conference transcript, 1988 July 25 (Box 60)
      Photocopied
    - American-Soviet youth orchestra reception, 1988 Aug. 29 (Box 60)
    - Induction of Sakharov to AAIAL, Spaso House, 1988 Sept. 9 (Box 60)
    - Shevardnadze visit to Washington, D.C., 1988 Sept. 22-23 (Box 60)
      Includes preparatory materials and press coverage
    - Chatauqua reception, 1988 Sept. 26 (Box 60)
    - US-Soviet Information Talks, Moscow, 1988 Sept. 26-28 (Box 60)
    - Paul Duke, Spaso House seminar, 1988 Sept. 27 (Box 60)
      Copy of introduction
    - Cleveland Quartet, Spaso House, 1988 Sept. 29 (Box 60)
    - High School Pairing Agreement signing, 1988 Oct. 1 (Box 60)
    - Interview with Nedelya newspaper, 1988 Oct. 3-4 (Box 60)
      Includes JM talking points, notes
    - Ditchley Foundations conference, 1988 Oct. 7-9 (Box 60)
    - "Information USA" exhibit, Minsk, 1988 Nov. 29 (Box 60)
    - Reagan-Gorbachev summit, New York City, 1988 Dec. (Box 60)
      Logistics and notes
    - "Ryijy Rugs" by RM exhibit, Buryat, ASSR, 1988 Dec. (Box 60)
      Pamphlet from exhibit
    - Earthquake in Armenia, 1988 Dec. 7; 2 folders (Box 60)
      Cables and press coverage of devestation and casualties; notes re: US response and internal memos re: US policy. Includes some photographs of JM and other unidentified people at what appears to be a scene from the earthquake -- it is unclear where and when these photographs were taken (JM did not go to the scene in 1988).
    - Pushkin Language Institute visit, 1988 Dec. 15 (Box 60)
    - Zhurkhovsky Military Academy visit, 1988 Dec. 19 (Box 60)
      Includes speech drafts, in Russian
    - Reports, clippings, and reference materials, 1989 (Box 61)
    - Memoranda, 1989; 3 folders (Box 61)
    - Correspondence from Soviet citizens, set aside by embassy staff, 1989 (Box 61)
      Selections from general correspondence identified as representative sampling by Moscow embassy staff for JM
    - Correspondence, 1989; 5 folders (Box 61)
    - Incoming unclassified cables, 1989; 8 folders (Box 62)
    - Press coverage and clippings of JM, 1989 (Box 63)
    - JM notes, 1989; 2 folders (Box 63)
      Largely loose pages or unidentified meeting notes
    - Moscow embassy security scandal press coverage, 1989 (Box 63)
      Regarding espionage accusations against Marines stationed at the Moscow embassy and subsequent policy changes for personnel
    - Moscow embassy newsletters, 1989 (Box 63)
    - Bush-Gorbachev communications (FOIA'd by JM, 2009), 1989 (Box 63)
    - USSR Supreme Soviet membership list, 1989 June (Box 63)
    - Reference book of Soviet officials, 1989 (Box 63)
      Compiled for JM. Includes Soviet Supreme, People's Congress, committees, and other information
    - Argumenti and Fakti interview, 1989 (Box 63)
      Edited Russian transcripts
    - Mementoes and souvenir pamphlets, 1989 (Box 63)
    - Invitations, programs, and events, 1989; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Guest lists, schedules, and calendars, 1989; 5 folders (Box 63)
    - Sec. of State Schultz and Shevardnadze talks, Paris, 1989 Jan. 8 (Box 63)
    - Diplomatic Academy at Soviet Foreign Ministry, 1989 Jan. 12; 2 folders (Box 63)
      Lecture by JM, in Russian. Includes photographs
    - Certificate of authenticity for Soviet RSD-10 (SS-20) Missile fragment from Kapustin Yor site, 1989 Jan. 14 (Box 63)
      Missile fragment not included
    - Dartmouth Conference: Arms Control Task Force, Moscow, 1989 Jan. 15-18 (Box 63)
    - Evening of Poetry with Nemerov and Grushko, Spaso House, 1989 Jan. 25 (Box 63)
    - Yunost' Radio interview, 1989 Feb. 2 (Box 63)
    - Smithsonian delegation dinner, Spaso House, 1989 Feb. 10 (Box 63)
    - Kuibyshev Military Engineering Academy visit, 1989 Feb. 24 (Box 63)
      Address by JM
    - National Council of Churches reception, Spaso House, 1989 Feb. 27 (Box 63)
    - Trip to Washington and Vienna, 1989 Mar. 2-5 (Box 63)
      Includes JM and RM logistics, notes, travel documents
    - Event at Dom Kino, 1989 Mar. 24 (Box 63)
      Includes audience questions for JM from Q and A (in Russian)
    - Spaso House seminar with Ampart Lowry Wyman, 1989 Mar. 19-Apr. 2 (Box 63)
      Seminar on March 27.
    - Trip to Washington, Greensboro, New York, Durham, 1989 Mar. 30-Apr. 11 (Box 63)
      Includes materials from several speaking engagements as well as home leave for JM and RM
    - Spaso House seder, 1989 Apr. 20 (Box 63)
    - Press briefing for Soviet journalists, Spaso House, 1989 Apr. 24 (Box 63)
    - Kurchatov Institute, 1989 Apr. (Box 63)
      Survey questions leftover following event
    - US-USSR Ministerial with Sec. of State Baker, Helsinki, 1989 May 9-12 (Box 63)
      Includes travel and meetings in Moscow, Brussels
    - "Signing of the Constitution" sculpture dedication, Spaso House, 1989 May 23 (Box 63)
    - Visit of Minneapolis Children's Theatre, Spaso House, 1989 June 1 (Box 64)
    - "Soviet Union in the 1990s" conference, IHT, Moscow, 1989 June 7 (Box 64)
    - Trip to Izhevsk and Votkinsk, 1989 June 9-10 (Box 64)
      Includes speech notes, travel materials, photograph of JM at the US Portal Monitoring Facility in Votkinsk
    - "Whither Gorbachev?" seminar, Washington DC, 1989 June 24-27 (Box 64)
      Includes post-seminar book from Center for Naval Analyses, speech notes by JM
    - Anschutz Collection luncheon, Spaso House, 1989 June 29 (Box 64)
    - Showing of film "Moonstruck," Spaso House, 1989 June 29 (Box 64)
    - Van Cliburn's charity concert, Moscow, 1989 July 3 (Box 64)
      Includes JM remarks
    - Embassy Moscow July 4th festivities, 1989 July 4 (Box 64)
    - JM July 4th television address, 1989 July 4 (Box 64)
      Includes preparations
    - Trip to Karelia, 1989 July 23-25 (Box 64)
    - Seminar with Gerald Janacek, Nekrosov, at Spaso House, 1989 July 27 (Box 64)
    - Imogen Cunningham exhibit, USIA, at Donskoy Monastery, 1989 July 27 (Box 64)
    - Black and White (Charlie Chaplin) cookout for Foreign Minister, 1989 Aug. (Box 64)